date: 5/28/2015
site: http://remodelthishouse.blogspot.com/

New Gear
Sorry for the week long delay. I am still around, just not posting lately. Shame on me! But I do have a good excuse...this:


Yep, I got a new <object value = "computer" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> computer </object> and haven't mastered it yet. I am working on it, and it is so hard to play on a new <object value = "computer" id = "0" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> computer </object>...let me tell ya. *wink*  Even Paris can hardly stay awake.


The problem is that I haven't transferred my <object value = "pictures" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> pictures </object> over so I can't share any projects. I will get this done asap. Anyways, I need some advice on apps. What do you like, use, love, etc.? I'm open to any suggestions!
Posted by Bethany 8 comments
Email This
BlogThis!
Share to Twitter
Share to Facebook
Share to Pinterest

9.19.2011
Happy Fall Y'all
The first day of fall might not be until the 23rd, but I decided to finally be early on something and get my <object value = "mantel" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> mantel </object> looking a little more fall-ish...especially since it was still decorated in <object value = "spring decor" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> spring decor </object>. Actually, it was a mixture of spring and summer. But that is no excuse, it looked not-put-together and was in need of serious attention. So I took 5 minutes to make it presentable.

I didn't want to go with traditional fall colors, pumpkins, or leaves. I did the traditional fall decor last year, so I thought a change was needed. This year I went with a neutral color palette with touches of warm, rustic colors.  Here is what I managed to rummage from the <object value = "house" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "em"> house </object>:


The decor is simple...which is a change for me. Usually I really play it up with lots of colors and elements, but I really like the changes. On the left side, I staked some <object value = "books" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> books </object> and topped them with a <object value = "candle holder" id = "6" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> twine-wrapped candle holder </object> and a <object value = "brass owl" id = "7" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> small brass owl </object>. I also layered my <object value = "chalkboard" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> diy chalkboard </object> in front of a <object value = "window" id = "9" type = "perm" agreement = "s"> window </object>. This <object value = "chalkboard" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> chalkboard </object> is an <object value = "chalkboard" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> upcycled thrift store frame </object> that I use and reuse for every season.


The right side of the <object value = "mantel" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> mantel </object> has a <object value = "lantern" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> tall lantern </object> with another <object value = "candle holder" id = "6" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> twine-wrapped candle holder </object>. Then I placed a <object value = "glass" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> glass full of corks </object> on top of my <object value = "spool" id = "12" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> vintage spool </object>. Finally I hung a set of <object value = "keys" id = "13" type = "perm"> metal keys </object> from the <object value = "window" id = "9" type = "perm" agreement = "s"> window </object> with <object value = "twine" id = "14" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> twine </object>. 


Easy, easy, easy. And the decor is versatile enough to last through Thanksgiving. I don't plan to decorate for Halloween so I should be good to go for a few months...yay!
Posted by Bethany 16 comments
Email This
BlogThis!
Share to Twitter
Share to Facebook
Share to Pinterest

Labels: fall decor, mantel
9.15.2011
Lavish
This <object value = "blog" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> post </object>is going to be more diary-ish than any other. I'm typing what I feel. If you don't want to read my musings, then just click here for the <object value = "website" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> website </object>.

I always have ideas running through my head. It is part of the reason why I don't sleep well at night, I can't turn the brain off. And one idea/dream has really stuck with me - having a funky boutique with lots of charm called Lavish. I finally feel like I am being led along this path and that my dream could actually become a reality. I don't know what will come of it, but if I don't start walking towards it, I will never make it.

It started out with this <object value = "blog" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> blog </object>, my first public appearance and showing of DIY projects and decor. It was scary, still is sometimes, to put my <object value = "house" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> house </object> and life out for public viewing and comments. But I have loved every second of it and each comment makes me smile, even if some aren't the nicest. It seems like everyone loves my thrifty repurposing and <object value = "furniture rehabs" id = "19" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> furniture rehabs </object>. Truth is, most of the <object value = "furniture rehabs" id = "19" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> furniture rehabs </object> aren't for my <object value = "house" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> house </object>...they are just because I love to fix something up. They sit in my <object value = "garage" id = "20" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> garage </object>, at my parents' house, or in the <object value = "storage unit" id = "21" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> storage unit </object> collecting dust.

So I have just been living life and <object value = "blog" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> blogging </object> a little when a friend told me that I should sign up for a booth at EcoFest, which I did. Moment of madness? Anyways, I worked and worked (and recruited my parents to work and work) to get ready. I had no clue who would come, what would happen, or if I would even have anyone enter my <object value = "EcoFest booth" id = "22" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> booth </object>. There was no turning back though - I paid my booth fee and was testing the waters a little deeper with an actual booth, not just <object value = "pictures" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> pictures </object> online.

And you know what? The booth was a hit! Everyone loved the items, said the booth was the "must see", and continually asked where my store front was. Did you catch that....where is my store! I was over the moon because actually hearing the words from complete strangers gave me a huge leap towards my dream, not just a step. That huge leap is confidence. Now I know that I can do this.

To continue along the path, I now have a <object value = "website" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "em"> website </object> for Lavish. A bonafide, grown-up, .com <object value = "website" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> website </object> - www.lavishyou.com. The <object value = "website" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> site </object> has information about furniture rehabs and e-decorating, but still needs a lot of work. (It is brand new, cut me a little slack.) The plan is to modify the <object value = "website" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> site </object> to fit my *hopefully* ever-growing business and one-day store front. I would be so happy if you would hop on over to <object value = "website" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> Lavish </object> and take a look around. Please let me know what you think...be it good or bad.

What does the future hold? I have no idea. But I do know that there will be some major life changing decisions and moments in the year to come. I am going to continue walking down the dream path, side-by-side with my family, and see where it takes us.

Posted by Bethany 9 comments