Date: 5/13/2015
Site: http://tarraandduchess.blogspot.com/

Click for the Clean it Out - Wednesday 5/13 Link List.
Yesterday we kept stuff in, so today let's clear stuff out.  What is in your diabetic closet that needs to be cleaned out?  This can be an actual physical belonging, or it can be something you're mentally or emotionally hanging on to.  Why are you keeping it and why do you need to get rid of it?  (Thank you Rick of RA Diabetes for this topic suggestion.)

I know over the years I have been listed as uncompliant in my medical files. The saddest part is that I was trying. I know now even with the best A1c I have ever had I know my previous Endocrinologist listed me as uncompliant Even though I worked really hard on reviewing my number and making changes as necessary. I know my current family practice Dr. lists me as uncompliant because of the fact I have complications and even thought my A1c is excellent. I work very hard to keep lows at bay and keep my Retinopathy under control in fact I only see the Retina Specialist twice a year because it is considered stable currently.

I know it infuriates me that they make assumptions the minute you mention complications which to some Dr.'s means I don't try, don't test and don't care but I find it insulting that they write me off. They tend to not give patients the benefit of the doubt. I know that so many people including nurses feel that they are free to comment negatively to the patient because you have complications. I wish they would teach physicians not to use the word uncompliant with Diabetic patients. I know I do request my medical records and I do read what they say. I have fired Dr.'s after reading the medical records. I hire them for a service not for judgement.

I know I wish more Dr.'s would understand that being a Diabetic is not easy and getting perfect numbers is not possible. I also wish they would at least look at my current A1c. I know I went to my current eye Dr.  who referred me to my  current Retina Specialist. I know I told him my Alc has been been below 7 for 7 years now. I happened that day to have a copy of my A1c and he seemed shocked. I know he mentioned most of his patients A1c is not that great but was surprised I had Retinopathy. I know Dr.'s are human but I have personally experienced way too much assuming and not enough checking by Dr.'s the past couple of years. I really wish they would move toward not using the word uncompliant because it is really defeating statement to the patients who really are trying.

I know I can't change much except addressing the Dr. I currently see. I have requested that one Dr. remove the word uncompliant from my file because I showed him my A1c and my graphs all the Diabetes data. I don't find it fair that I am automatically considered to be a bad patient when I work so hard. I am trying to let this go emotionally but I know it will take time to get over the fact that I can't change all Dr.'s. I am hoping that some day they won't use that term about any Diabetic but for now I can only hope that someday that is the case.
Posted by Tarra at 6:42 AM No comments: 

Tuesday, May 12, 2015
Blog Week Post #2 Keep it to Yourself
                                                
  Blog Week Post #2 Keeping it to yourself

Click for the Keep it to Yourself - Tuesday 5/12 Link List.
Many of us share lots of aspects of our diabetes lives online for the world to see.  What are some of the aspects of diabetes that you choose to keep private from the internet?  Or from your family and friends?  Why is it important to keep it to yourself?  (This is not an attempt to get you out of your comfort zone.  There is no need to elaborate or tell personal stories related to these aspects.  Simply let us know what kinds of stories we will never hear you tell, and why you won't tell them.) (Thank you Scott E of Rolling in the D for this topic.)


I know I have always prided myself on sharing everything including the moments of scary which I have had quite a few of the past seven year in particular. The certain areas I don't share on my blogs is who I am dating and if I am single etc. I feel that if I was married I might share a small bit but I am most comfortable just leaving that information out. I know another area I won't share is other conditions outside my Diabetes except the one's that are other Endocrine issues.

I know I do have Rheumatoid Arthritis, Celiac's Disease, Diabetic Retinopathy and Hypoglycemia Unawareness. I have always shared as I develop complications right away on my blog. I have found that I feel better if I share as it is happening. I know I did with my Retinopathy Diagnosis but I had Hypoglycemia for several years before I started my blog. I like to share as it happens because at one time I was looking for another person who was going through the same complication but found no blogs. That is why I started blogging back in May of 2012. Sharing my Diabetes related information is wonderful in that I can put this stuff I am carrying around online instead of on my own shoulders. 

I know this past year in January I would not disclose what type of procedure I was having because it was not Diabetes related but I blogged about it because it was causing many issues for me with my Diabetes. I feel that sharing exactly the issue was best kept to myself because I know I needed the privacy I know I wished I could share but I know that it really was best left unsaid. I am doing so much better now with the quick procedure that was done and my graphs on my Dexcom are almost back to they way they were back when I first started on the Dexcom. I honestly had no idea how much the issues was causing issues with my Diabetes which does happen. I am thankful I had a wonderful Dr. who my Endocrinologist recommended. I know I think we all have some things that are just not appropriate for our blogs. I know I felt better in the long run not discussing it and I know having some privacy is really nice in times like these.

I know I am hoping you all understand the reasoning behind not sharing my procedure and my dating life because I think that information might create issues. I know if you list a person on your blog anyone can read it and so you also need to think about them. So by leaving the off the blog I can discuss them without naming them but I find it is just better to keep my that off my blog and just in my personal life. There will always be parts of our lives we won't share. 
Posted by Tarra at 6:40 AM No comments: 

Monday, May 11, 2015
Diabetes Blog Week " I Can"
                                                 

Yeah Diabetes Blog Week: Let’s get started!  Today’s topic is I Can.  In the UK, there was a diabetes blog theme of "I can...”  that participants found wonderfully empowering.  So lets kick things off this year by looking at the positive side of our lives with diabetes.  What have you or your loved one accomplished, despite having diabetes, that you weren't sure you could?  Or what have you done that you've been particularly proud of?  Or what good thing has diabetes brought into your life?  (Thank you to the anonymous person who submitted this topic suggestion.)



I know I wake up each day knowing that their will always be challenges for everyone including Diabetics. I really wish that my father would understand it's not 1980 anymore. My father when I wanted to run a half marathon said it was too dangerous and Diabetics should not be running half marathons but I disagree I know plenty who have. I am still planning to run a half marathon but after I explore some other adventures I want to go on. I know a big part of the reason my father thinks this is because I can't feel lows but he also has only seen the occasional low when I visit at Christmas so he really has not real concept of what my life is like today. I did have a low that needed assistance but my dad could have given me a glucagon shot and been fine. 

I know each year my goal is always the same to reduce my lows and I get better at doing so the longer I have had Hypoglycemia Unawareness. I know I will have added precautions and planning even for non exercise activities. I am okay with that because you get used to those changes. I know my father about lost it when I told him next year I am planning to go to California to get Accelerated Free Fall training basically solo skydiving. I know most people are thinking wow that is dangerous. I know most of the adrenaline junkie activities I love are dangerous but I am never as happy as when I am going on my next adrenaline rush. I know I also plan for example zip lining, and a couple new adventures as well. I know I won't let Diabetes win.

I know I will have critics who think I am reckless or foolish but I know me and what I love. Life is about living the life you want and some times getting the adrenaline rush is exactly what I needed. I know I went sky diving back in March and I was in a high for three days afterwards and I never stopped smiling. I felt like I had my zest for life back and I am so know this is what I have been missing in my life. I know some of my family is like that is awesome you love sky diving and others are like you can't do that. I know I can and I will be doing it. The issue for me normally isn't me doubting that I can do it but normally my family or others.

I do plan on running a half marathon but that has been put on hold while I pursue skydiving for a while. I do plan on pushing myself to achieve my goals and dreams. I have been told no so many times in my life but I have always been able to accomplish these goals. I know when my Endocrinologist tells me that I can go skydiving I should be fine. I know I told her my plan I have for skydiving and she looked at my graph for the day and she said I looked great. I also get better at planning these activities. Also a word of advice don't have the Dr. notate in your file you are sky diving if you injure yourself the insurance won't cover it. 

I am so over joyed that I am going to do skydiving because I can and honestly I deserve to be happy like any other person does. I am tired of my father trying to trap me into the thought process of the time I was diagnosed where they limited everything in life. I know with all these incredible Diabetic athletes why could I not. I know my body has always given me so many challenges but I do not give up easily and I will continue to search for my next crazy fun activity because life is so much better when I do.
Posted by Tarra at 6:23 AM 10 comments: 

Friday, May 8, 2015
When Juggling Several Conditions at Once
I know at time it is so easy forget I even have Rheumatoid Arthritis since I was 19. I know most of the time it is just in the background and I don't have to do much. I know since my last flare up I have never really got back to where I was previously. I know I have noticed changes in my hands and my ability to open the plastic bags in the produce section is almost always too much for me to handle. I know I am thrilled with my current medication but it seems to work okay but I am worried about the long term changes with my hands. I know recently I have noticed that in the mornings when I am at my stiff I have trouble opening doors now and I have noticed it can at times be painful to be typing on the computer in the mornings until I have gotten my joints loosened up. I know I want Duchess to help at times by pressing the button on the door but they are so stiff she can't. So I am stuck having to hit the button which hurts. So I know I need to discuss this with my Dr. next week.

I know she has always considered my RA to be mild and not even moderate but with the recent changes I am not sure what to think. I know I work out frequently but normally I seem to handle it pretty well. I do know that the recent changes make me really nervous that I won't get back to the way things used to be. I know my current medication Methotrexate worked really well at first but not so much now. I know it is supposed to help stop the progression of my RA but I feel like that is not the case currently. Another issue I have found is that normally with Methotrexate you can't use advil. Sadly my Dexcom will not tolerate the use of acetaminophen. So basically if I hurt myself I can't use any pain relief medications.

I know I tend to be clumsy at times and I have had to just grin and bear it but at other times I take the risk and take the Advil. I know this is not recommended because it reduces the effectiveness of the Methotrexate. So I have only done it once or twice. So now I am questioning in general what I can do. I am hoping my Dr. will help me find a solution but I am feeling more and more like this current medication is not for me. I know I am willing to try new medications with the hopes they last right up to when I can take my next dose. I know most of the time I feel the medication wearing off on Tuesday night and I can't take more till Thursday night so technically I might just need a higher dosage but trying to juggle my needs, need to avoid Tylenol because of the Dexcom just makes things even more complicated.  

I know at times I worry way too much about my collection of autoimmune disorders I am collecting which include Diabetes, Rheumatoid Arthritis, and Celiac's disease. I know my conditions tend to show up in ways I am not always expecting but hopefully I can find some relief soon.
Posted by Tarra at 8:37 AM No comments: 

Thursday, May 7, 2015
Messing with the Dexcom Numbers
I love the concept of the Dexcom and what it can do for most people. I know I am the exception in that my numbers on the Dexcom tend to inaccurate for example last nigh. I ate dinner as usual and I head to the gym. I start working out and I expect to see my blood sugars rise during the beginning of my work out since I do not bolus for my meal before going to the gym. So I start working out and I am 20 minutest into my workout and I look at my Dexcom and it has one pointed straight up but I was expecting to see my Dexcom showing that it was leveling off and will be showing a drop. So I continued working out another five minutes. Then Duchess runs over to my machine and stares at me. I know the look when I need to check. So I finish the last two minutes and then test. Sure enough I was actually 69 and the Dexcom still had me moving up when I was actually low.

I know during these times having Duchess is really important. A great deal of the time my Dexcom will say it is moving up quickly when it is not most of the time. So I always test to see where I actually am. I know even when I have had bad lows where I needed assistance normally 40 minutes after the event the Dexcom finally catches up. I am not sure why there is such a delay but I also know that Medtronic's CGM is even worse for me. So I do the best I can with the information I have. I have recently moved my CGM blood sugar down when I start working out. By starting my blood sugar levels at a lower than my actual number has helped improve the accuracy of the alerts some what I am seeing it alert ten minutes after my low instead of 40 minutes. I have not run into any issues with doing so. I was worried about highs but that has not been an issue so far.

Posted by Tarra at 7:57 AM No comments: 

Wednesday, May 6, 2015
Changing Needs
I know recently I have noticed that my Rheumatoid Arthritis medication does not seem to be working as well as it once was. I am not sure if I need a higher dosage or just need to change medications. I know the Methotrexate for the most part has worked well but it really has some down sides to taking this medication. I do lose more of my hair than normal, it tend to catch more colds and  I can't drink more than two drinks in one week. I know most of the time it seems to work okay but an issue I have noticed is that by Wednesday of each week I can feel more pain and stiffness. It is like the medication stops on Tuesday evening and I am unable to take more until Thursday evening. I know each morning I have noticed that I have had increasing difficulty with my hands and being able to get my body to function like normal. So I know my up coming appointment with my Rheumatologist I know I have some issue to discuss.

I am not really sure what the Dr. is going to recommend but after a year of the Methotrexate I am not feeling like it is for me. I am hoping she is willing to help me find a drug that will not have as many restrictions like Methotrexate does such as I have to limit sun exposure which is difficult when living in Texas. I also need to avoid people who are sick because it does suppress the immune system. Then I am not able to even enjoy the occasional drink with friends because it can elevate the levels of your liver which is not good.  So I know I am not really happy at this point and I am hoping they have other options available but I also know my insurance only covers one or two RA medications currently the rest are not covered. So my choices are limited which does not help. All I know is that today at work I have needed to get up more because my medication does seem effective enough. Hoping I can get some results I need soon.


Posted by Tarra at 10:45 AM No comments: 

Tuesday, May 5, 2015
My Retinopathy Experience
I know I have been thinking back to my Retinopathy Diagnosis several years ago. I know I started my blog around the time my Retinopathy showed up in my life. I remember I woke up one morning and noticed black spots in my vision which were small hemorrhages in my eye. I went to the eye Dr. that day because I was concerned. He took one look and said that I had a Retina Detachment. So I was told with my eyes dilated I needed to go to the Retina Specialist now.  So I left the office very scared. I know they rushed me back immediately when I arrived at the Retina Specialist office. The nurse comes in and starts to ask me questions. I know she said they believe I have Retinopathy and I knew that was most likely the case. The nurse then says to me I guess you should have taken better care of yourself. I told the nurse that was not the case and I did not deserve to be treated this way. I told her to leave her judgement at the door.

Next thing the Dr. comes in and looks at my eye. He says the good news is that I don't have a Retina Detachment but I do have Retinopathy. I also had quite a few new blood vessels which are leaking and hemorrhaging. So they say I need to be treated immediately. The Dr. says to help stop of the bleeding I need to have an injection into my eye. I know when he said that I was shocked that was what they were going to do. I have always had a thing about anything being close to my eye so it was difficult. I hated the injections they were not painful but they worked really well. Then I was told I needed to come back for more procedures which they used dyes which could show the blood flow in the eyes called an angiogram. They also did regular pictures and other exams. I know it was an overwhelming experience and I know I was extremely scared at the time. I decided that I would take things one day at a time. I also knew that I wanted to make sure my A1c was under 6.5 to prevent any further complications and I actually had been in that range for several years so I just needed to make sure I stayed in range.

I know they then said I needed laser procedures done which I was okay with. I had no idea that it could be as painful as it was. I also had no idea that my Retina specialist at the time was not following the standard procedure for doing laser procedures. He had me laying back in a chair trying to laser my eye but that did not work because my eye was watering the whole time. Normally you are in an up right position sitting as the Dr. does the laser procedure. I know my Dr. then told me I needed to have a Vitrecotomy since the laser was not working. I know that seemed wrong he only tried twice to laser my eyes. So I went to get a second opinion. I meet another young woman who had Retinopathy and she spent time talking with me. I found out that if you do have a Vitrectomy you could also need further surgeries and she had several. She told me to try and see if the laser procedures worked first and not to jump into surgery.

So I took her advice. I changed Retina Specialist and he did laser procedures and  a year and half later I have had not procedures done and no bleeding. So I know the surgery seems like a good idea but for me I knew I just wanted to avoid the surgery if at all possible. So for me it worked. I know my experience is not typical but we need to all communicate what we need. For me avoiding surgery has been a blessing and I today still have 20/20 vision and no new blood vessel growth in my eyes. I do work everyday to keep my eyes healthy by keep my Alc in a good range and exercising.

I know this journey was scary and I encourage everyone to share because I know I did not find any one sharing their experiences several years ago. It can be incredibly scary but I know for me I found taking it one day at a time made it all manageable. I also did a great deal of research which helped me have realistic expectations. I know I felt better knowing about procedures before they were done. So I made it a point to read up and educate myself. I know I don't know what I would have done without my friend online who shared her experience. I know I made the decisions I needed to make for me. I know I learned I need to advocate for myself as well. I know some of the best advice my Dr. gave me is to sleep on two pillows to help keep blood from flowing into your field of vision when sleeping. Most hemorrhages happen when you are asleep.  My first Retina Specialist did not share this advice so I felt he just was their for the money always wanting me to go for a surgery. I know I have never been happier to fire a Dr. than that one.

I know today my eyes are doing great and I hope to see them continue to be in good condition. I know I have learned so much from my experience. I also did not realize how strong I was until I walked this road alone. I know I hope everyone continues to share their experiences because it means the world to someone who is going through it completely scared. I know that my combination of therapies of injections, laser and keeping A1c down have all helped me to get my Retinopathy stable and stay stable the past several years.
Posted by Tarra at 7:17 AM 4 comments: 
Email This
BlogThis!
Share to Twitter
Share to Facebook
Share to Pinterest

Monday, May 4, 2015
35 Years Where Did The Time Go
I know last year I really was struggling with my Diaversary but this year is so much different. I know my goal this year was to make my Diaversary a little more fun. I know growing up we never celebrated me making it another year or did anything on the date. In fact I don't know the exact date of my diagnosis. My mother would have possible know the date but she passed away seven years ago. So I have not idea except that my mother told me I was diagnosed when I was 18 months old at all my Dr. appointments. I was diagnosed back in 1980 boy does this make me feel old but back to the subject at hand. So this I woke up that day feeling completely in awe that I have Type 1 Diabetes and that no matter what has happened even with dealing with complications I feel like I have accomplished a great deal. I know I am so happy that my Retinopathy has been stable that my vision is still 20/20 even with my Retinopathy. I am also proud that I found solutions for all the issues my Diabetes has thrown at me.

I know I have done the best I can over the years and I am proud that even with my Hypoglycemia Unawareness that it has not stopped me. I still jump out of planes, run and exercise like everyone else. The only thing that has changed is that I have to pre-plan everything out but at the end of the day it is really a small change. I know I have had to learn so much from my Hypoglycemia Unawareness it has taught me to appreciate things even more. It has taught me to really pay more attention to what foods and I am eating and how it affects my blood sugar. I know through it all I am still shocked it has been 35 years. I know I am proud and I know my mother would have been proud as well.

I know my life with Type 1 Diabetes has never been easy and will continue to be full of challenges. i know my Diabetes has taught me to be incredibly resourceful and creative in finding solutions. I know I also owe my parents a great deal gratitude for doing an exceptional job of managing my Type 1 Diabetes. They were incredible in their dedication. I also admire how they found ways to make the worst part of Diabetes more fun when ever possible. I am sitting here today in awe of it all. I also I am thankful that I continue to work at my Diabetes. I know I would not be the same person today without my Diabetes and I am celebrating that today. I am also celebrating I have been blogging for three years now. It is incredible how much my blog has changed my life for the better as well. Thank you all for reading and following me on my journey. 
