Date: 5/13/2015
Site: http://livinglifebreathlessly.blogspot.com/

Living life breathlessly
“Life is not measured by the number of breaths we take, but by the moments that take our breath away”

Tuesday, May 12, 2015
infection relief
So I've been complaining about shortness of breath in my last few blog posts when walking or climbing stairs (more than I'm used to or expect with 40%-ish lung function). So yesterday morning when I was out of breath after just walking from my car to desk at work, and after feeling sooooo tired lately I decided to go to the Dr, even though he can't treat my chronic rejection any more than it's already being treated and even though I was there just over 2 weeks ago.

Had bloods done, x-ray, lung function (wasn't down by as much as I expected given how crap I felt) was 38% FEV1%, 6 min walk test (O2 sats were about 94% when I started with a heart-rate of 133, which is high, even for me! After 6 mins of relatively fast walking it was 83% and HR 159). Still felt like it should have been worse judging by how I felt.

Then the bloods showed elevated white cell count and CRP (ie infection) and I felt sssoooo relieved! Even more relived when I had a temp of 38.7 degrees C and Dr said my chest sounds crap even though I'm not coughing at all! It means it's actually something that can be TREATED and not just my lungs suddenly deciding to decline way faster just before our US trip just to piss me off! Must have picked up something at work (where SO MANY people have been sick and it sounds like a hospital waiting room with all the sneezing and coughing), but who cares right? Corporate Culture dictates that you go to work, not matter how sick. Chris has also been sick (thanks to someone at HIS work who sits across from him and came in on Thursday VERY sick). THIS is why some post transplant patients DON'T work at all, but I wanted a normal life which comes with this risk so it's just something I have to deal with.

Luckily I wasn't admitted (not that I would have minded too much, sometimes you just want to feel better) but sent home with oral antibiotics for 2 weeks, Slow-K (guessing potassium was low), 30mg of Prednisone for 5 days and 2 inhalers. Also been booked off for the rest of the week with strict instructions to REST. This is NOT a problem as I really feel I need the rest.

Hopefully by the weekend I'll feel like a brand new person and can carry on looking forward to our American Dream holiday.


Happy Mother's Day, 2 months and lungs
Been an EXTREMELY fast weekend, it's INSANE that it is over already :-( I didn't even get to sleep late properly :-(. uuuggghhhhh

Mother's Day lunch was great though (apart from Chris missing it due to being sick). My sis made yummy food and it was just great discussing all our travels (parentals are also going overseas soon!). Poor Chris caught a bad cold/flu at work and has been suffering for last 3 days now. I cannot believe I haven't gotten sick between him and all the sick people at work!!! Bloody immune system is too strong :-(


Fed a friend of mine's two doggies for the weekend, two awesome black spaniels! Took them for a short walk with my sis. Made me COMPLETELY out of breath... meh. She took over and took them for a short run while I waited for them. It's really felt like I am struggling more to breathe with exercise these last few days... making me stress!!!!! Today in exactly 2 months time we leave for San Fran. Lungs need to stick it out till then! Seriously!!! We've waited long for this so BEHAVE!!! You also know winter is here when they start burning the grass in Joburg..... which was the case at Albert's Farm where we walked the dogs. You can see the smoke on my pic below (edited using my new iPhone!). The buildings in the background is Rosebank.


My car is going in to be fixed this week after my bumper-bashing a few weeks ago, Wednesday is VISA day (take two), and hoping Chris get better! Also might try to see dermatologist again as one of the little warts he burnt off a while ago seems to be growing bask. Annoying!!!! Anyways... hopefully a productive week!!!


Posted by Alice at 7:51 PM No comments:
Labels: #StayStrong, BOS/Chronic Rejection, Jozi
Saturday, May 9, 2015
Early Mother's Day post!
Wanted to share the pics in an early Mother's Day post!  Love them! We are having lunch at my sister's house tomorrow, looking forward to it. My mom was 26 when she had me, and 29 when she had my sis. Crazy to think that when she was my age, she had to cope with a 2-year old and a 5-year old with a chronic disease (and bad prognosis at the time). She is probably the strongest woman I know, and the best role-model a girl can have. Growing up she was the perfect mix if caring and scary, and I guess that's what you need to be when raising a rebel-ish child with CF! And not to mention absolutely BEAUTIFUL, hopefully I have inherited her awesome-ageing genes as well!