date: 6/25/2015
site: http://willowwayblog.blogspot.com/2015/05/small-business-series-why-i-started.html

Small Business Series : Why I Started Willow Crowns


I'll occasionally get e-mails or questions on Instagram asking about WC, why I started it, how I balance it, how to make a small business successful, etc. I don't know that I'm particularly qualified to give advice on any of those, but I thought it might be a fun idea to do a small business series on the 'ol blog and talk about my experience as a (very) small business owner. 

A good place to start is at the beginning. Why I started Willow Crowns. If you've been hanging around here for long, you know it's a focus of my Instagram and a big part of my day to day life, which is something I really never expected.

Let me be super honest. I expected being a stay at home mom to completely fulfill me. I don't know why, since I had no experience with it, but I just kind of assumed it would be everything I needed/wanted and that it would be great not to have to "go to work" every day.

The first thing I learned is that motherhood is work. Whether you leave the house or don't, have a full time job outside of parenting or not, it's hard work and that you can't phone it in. 

The second thing I learned is that it didn't completely fulfill me. Don't get me wrong and don't get all riled up. I absolutely love staying home with my daughter and if I could only choose to do one thing, that's what I'd be doing, hands down. I would never trade this job and try to remember how lucky I am to have it, but there was a definite longing for something else that was coexisting with my love of motherhood.

Around the time O was 10 months old, I started to miss doing non mom things and feeling like I wanted to do something for myself. I think a big part of it was that I was two months into our move to Texas. Getting to know new people has never been a real strength of mine so I was pretty lonely in a brand new place with a husband who worked a lot. We were feeling stressed from buying our first home, a little isolated, Ryan's new job was kicking his butt, and it was honestly a really hard time for us. 

I was already making (the crappiest) little headbands for Liv (because I was going to punch the next person to tell me what a beautiful little boy I had), and thought I may as well see if I could sell some on Etsy. Maybe I could contribute a tiny bit financially, be creative, and have something that was mine. It was what I did during naps, late at night when I was still home alone with the baby, and it was really therapeutic. My early efforts were beyond embarrassing and if you bought something during those early days, I'm really really sorry. 

I really didn't know if it would grow or be a total dud, but it kind of didn't matter at the time. It was cathartic and gave me something to focus on besides the stress and unhappiness we were working through. It made me a better mom because I was doing something for myself, so I felt like I had more to give when it was "mom time". Does that make sense?

So that's how Willow Crowns was born. Crowns because duh, they're headbands and Willow for the name of the street I grew up on, the little piece of home I really needed at the time.


Pin on Pinterest

A couple of ideas I have for future posts are how I grew the business, talking about branding, time management while still being a full time stay at home mom, and anything else you'd like to know! Let me know in the comments if there's something you'd like to hear about related to WC or being a small business owner! 

xoxo

p.s. Steph has posted a live stream of her thoughts/actions from our Spring launch today and I think it's a fun read if you're interested!