date: 6/9/2015
site: http://mottmultiples.blogspot.com/

Wednesday, May 20, 2015
Twins..Triplets and A Single..Getting Busy With Life!
I settled into bed on Sunday evening at an early hour.  The weekend was overwhelming and I think I ate most of my meals on the road.  It was not a family vacation or anything but rather the life of a chauffeur mom.  We sent everyone in for showers early on Sunday evening with the hopes of the house shutting down early. 

We covered lots of highway miles, 5 hockey games, 2 baseball games, tennis practice, a 5k run and a date night on Saturday.  I laid down and got all covered up and cozy.  My intent was to let my eyes roll back in my head and drift into a deep slumber.  As soon as I hit the pillow my brain did the opposite.  What is ahead of me this week? 

Are all of the carpools set up? 
Is Colin's eye doctor appointment going to conflict with my volunteering in the classroom?  
Wait... is David working late any night this week? 
I need to order the mulch!  
Oh shoot I still need to send an email out about the hosting of the families at the homeless shelter.  
I really need to get the summer clothes out for the triplets.  
Did I change that last load of laundry?  

Needless to say I leaned over and told David, "I will be back later, I need to gather my thoughts for the week".  I needed to sit down and get the calendars out and write out all the requirements for the week.  I am still a little old fashioned in the spring when we are overbooked.  I keep everything in my phone on my calendar but there is something to be said about having it all written out so you can see the week in a glance and really see any gaps in the schedule.  Our biggest issue that now we have the triplets doing activities.  If everyone has an event on a single night I am just out of people.  It takes some patience and the ability to ask for help to be able to juggle and balance this interesting 6 week time period in the spring.  Liam plays baseball and the triplets also play baseball.  Eamon and Liam play spring hockey.  Mairin does swim and tennis.  Eamon and Liam also participate in the 7th grade tennis team thru school.  Some of the frustration comes with the overlapping of the seasons.  Baseball is wrapping up and swim tune up is beginning.  Spring hockey is ending but tennis has another week. 
Spring dinnertime is rough.  I have to come up with dinners that can sit on the stove and pick items that the kids will eat warm or cold.  Taco pie and blueberry pie was sitting on the stove last night for all of the shifts coming and going.  By the time I arrived home half of it was gone and it was still being eaten.  I can't keep up with the stains on the clothes and the kids are spending their evenings running around during the baseball games or hockey games.  There is not a lot of home time for the triplets because they usually have to ride with me to the events.  They never understand why they can't watch TV before bed on the nights when we don't get home until dark. 

I finish the organizing of my thoughts at the kitchen table around 11:30pm on Sunday night.  It was all I could do to make it back up the stairs and crawl into bed.  Monday proved to be a great morning because I had the week in a snapshot in my head and we ready to take on the week. 

Monday night we had an amazing experience.  Our church hosts 35 homeless people from the South Oakland Homeless Shelter every year for a week.  We provide the food for 3 meals a day.  They sleep at the our parish and we provide everything they need.  Our parish volunteers to take the people to their jobs, schools or to the shelters during the day and they all come back in the evenings.  We decided to take on the dinner for Monday evening.  I grabbed 4 other families from our parish and we got together to make a taco night with all the fixings.  The mom's made the food but the kids all served the dinner, helped clean up and then entertained the kids for the evening.  It was so enjoyable for all of us and definitely something we will do again in the future.

Posted by Heather Mott at 2:11 PM No comments:   Links to this post
Email This
BlogThis!
Share to Twitter
Share to Facebook
Share to Pinterest

Friday, April 24, 2015
Twins, Triplets and Single ....Deals and Dramas
We take up a whole row.  We need a bigger than average kitchen table.  We can’t take other kids with us because our vehicle is at capacity.  The benefits and the downfalls of a big family.  Family memberships to the zoo are beneficial to families like mine.  We can more than pay for a year membership in just a single visit.  Family discounts benefit us sometimes when they make prices lower after child number  4.  

Every time we go to sign the kids up for an event  and the price seems reasonable it is when you have to double or triple it and you start to get nauseous.  People always tell me about the cute little markets that they shop at and all the cool types of food they have.  I have walked into these stores and quickly remember why Costco and Sam’s Club are my trusty go to options.  I buy a dozen boxes of cereal when they are on sale because we are easily a box a morning.  I stop at the outlets on my way up north because Pepper ridge Farms has all of their bread next to the counter priced at 1.00 per loaf.  I will take bags of bread home and freeze.  I always say it is not so much the cost but the amount of storage needed for a big family.   I have a make shift pantry out in the garage where I can stock my dry goods and mostly it is stocked due to really good sales that I need to take advantage of. 

Easter is always interesting.  Our church is never full enough to where you can’t find a seat but on Easter you have to make sure and get there early in order to grab a seat.  This is especially true for us because the 8 of us take up an entire row.  The holidays (no matter which one it is) is always exhausting because the amount of work that goes into getting everyone dressed and ready in their fancy clothes is quite an undertaking.  Eamon wears a different size than liam does and they both have different size jackets.  The shoes if not worn in awhile could be too small and as they are complaining that their feet are curled up at the end I am saying, “deal with it, we are out of options and I have to move on and get the triplets dressed”.  There are 5 ties to be tied and  putting together enough belts to match and fit is always a problem.  They always disappear.  Then it is just when you are walking out to the car and you notice that Liam  didn’t go to his dad’s drawer and get a pair of black socks but that he is sporting those flouresent Under Armor socks that are peaking thru the gap of his khakis that could argueably be almost too short.  We cannot get the triplets dressed to early because they will ruin their outfits in no time.  We came home from a 1st communion just the other  night and as I was washing the clothes I had 2 dress shirts with rips in the arms, 1 dress shirt with orange marker on it, a blazer with a missing button (grrrrrrr) and 3 pairs of dress pants with grass stains on them.  Another day…..

Posted by Heather Mott at 11:04 AM 2 comments:   Links to this post
Email This
BlogThis!
Share to Twitter
Share to Facebook
Share to Pinterest

Saturday, March 28, 2015
The Spring Dance
The snow is melting and everything here in Michigan is looking grey and very drab.  Spring is around the corner but if you look outside you just can’t believe that it is close.  The only way to really begin anticipating spring is to see all the spring goods in the stores and take advantage of the increased hours of daylight.  Kids are starting their baseball season and everyone is scheduling around March Madness.  It is time for all of the spring sports to begin and for those of us hockey families, it is the beginning of the Spring Dance.  You would not understand it if you didn’t experience it.  You probably won’t believe me when I explain it. Those of you reading who are in hockey will get it and those of you who are not will question why in the heck do you participate in such craziness.    My husband calls it the Spring Dance and I think it is a very fitting name for what is about to occur.

We dedicate ourselves to a season of hockey that runs August through March.  We become friends with the other parents on our team because we spend more time together than we do with anyone else.  We are on the ice 3 days a week and often will add a game or conditioning session in there somewhere.  We all sit together and cheer on our boys.  It doesn’t take long to know each kid and know how they skate and what their number is.  You start to cheer on all the kids on your team and celebrate their victories as if they are all your own children.  Your heart drops when one gets injured and you feel like it is your own.  You spend weekends together either in hotels or locally waiting for the games to start.  Some rinks stink and leak and some are wonderful.  We enjoy finding restaurants that  will take a reservation for 40 after a tournament game.  I have witnessed hide and go seek in Meijers (just to kill some time in between games), skating parties on our pond or other man made arenas in backyards.  I have watched 12 year old boys say dumb things and make messes while showing off in front of their friends at a hockey dinner.  I have carpooled with different families and have visited many team members homes for team gatherings.   My boys have made so many friends throughout the years of hockey and we have learned to never burn a bridge as you will probably share a team with that person again in the future. 

We never dreamed we would be a hockey family.   We never played hockey and we really never had friends who played.  All it took was a neighbor who had a son 6 years older than my oldest who asked if they could use the pond in our backyard to skate on, one winter 8 years ago.  The boys put on their skates and watched the neighbor boy and it was over.  They learned to skate on our pond and wanted more.  We started with a tot hockey program and proceeded to play house for 2 years.  The boys improved and we decided to join the ranks of the crazy people and dove into a “beginner travel team”.  By beginner I mean “a glorified house team with more ice time”.  We never traveled very far and the cost was reasonable.  Most of all the boys loved it.  They always kept excellent grades and never ever complained about an early practice or having to miss something because of hockey. They love it, they crave it and they want more of it.  Eamon always says, “there is nothing better than a weekend with a hockey tournament and I can be on the ice all weekend” We don’t plan much in the winter months because hours are spent on the pond skating.  I usually snow blow while the kids are at school and then they come out after school and shovel so that the puck will skim across the ice. 

Let’s talk more about the dance.  The season often ends mid March and it is not a week later that tryouts are upon us.  The spring hockey season is short..about 6 to 8 weeks.   It can be a critical time to make moves because you can better secure your fall spot if you choose that team in the spring.  You will see talent move from one team to another year after year.  I once heard a coach say that the best part of hockey was the end of the season when the coaches would fight and steal kids and the mystery and anticipation of what team will end up being the best.    Spring is the only time you can double roster and the coaches carry bigger teams.  You could also call it an extended tryout.  End of February and beginning of March is when everyone shuts down.  People don’t talk about what they are going to do.  There is no talk of staying on the team or leaving.  The funny part is that most people won’t ask others what they are doing either.  It is a very weird secret time in the hockey world.    This is when teams can fall apart.  There are times when groups get together and will all leave together..secretly.   There is also lots of talk about who is at tryouts.  You could happen to run into someone at a tryout who is on your team and it is usually an awkward moment.  People will often talk about who they saw at another tryout and everyone is always at tryouts to see who is showing up.  “Is there any new talent coming to our tryouts” is a common question among the men folk.   You will see a cluster of dads standing around acting like they have to be there for their kids tryout but secretly none of them let their wives take the kids because this is like a prime time social event, a presidential ball where your child is being presented on the ice and everyone is watching.  Don’t  let any dad fool you that they are not reliving their childhood and  experiencing an adrenaline rush just being there for their kids.  

After try outs everyone goes about their business and it is only until all the tryouts are closed and the rosters are posted do you really know what people are doing.  Every year we are usually blown away with some of the moves but I guess this is part of the game of hockey.     This is the part that stresses me out the most.  Some years we spend time deciding what to do and some years we don’t try out for any teams other than our current one.  This year was the year we chose to entertain some tryouts.   It brought back the stress and the anxiety.   The little’s are getting older and they are now doing their own sports and we were playing on a team that was a solid 30 minutes away.  We have 2 teams that are literally in our backyard and we wanted to check them out.   Spring is by far, the craziest time of the year for my family and requires David and me to coordinate schedules and be on our A game.   I have recently added all the upcoming events to my calendar and have realized that I will have to enlist a fellow driver to help us out this year.  There are too many evenings when we have 3 places to be.


In the end after several weeks of trying out and talking about things we decided that we will be making a move for spring to a team that might (and I stress might) be a little bit better than our current team and it is for sure a lot closer (11 minutes away).  We did the dance this year.   We made our commitment this past Sunday to a new team and although we disappointed some people and surprised others we are happy with our decision because it was right for our family.
