date: 05/28/2015
site: https://myelephantsintheroom.wordpress.com/

HALF A YEAR WITH HALF A LEG
 Six months ago, at this exact moment, I was hyperventilating in my hospital room and trying to come to terms with the fact that I was about to have part of my leg removed.  Woah.  In some ways it feels like I just had my surgery a few weeks ago, but in other ways, it feels like I’ve been an amputee my whole life.

The past six months have been nothing short of incredible.  I’ve grown, I’ve changed, and I’ve become stronger.  I’ve been constantly reminded of just how great the little things in life are.  As a result of the event that occurred on November 25, 2014 I’ve had some amazing experiences, including speaking at schools and retreats, being part of a council at the hospital, and participating in a commercial.  I finished my first post-amp 5K, dipped my toes in the ocean for the first time in years, and learned how to <object value = "car" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> drive </object> again.

I’d be lying if I said that the past six months have been perfect or without challenges.  It certainly has not been easy.  My patience has been tested as I have had to wait for things: a <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object>, the ability to <object value = "car" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> drive </object>, and the freedom to walk unassisted, to name a few.  I’ve worked through post-op pain, discomfort from overuse of my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> leg </object>, and soreness from tough PT sessions.  But although it did not all come easily, it’s all been beyond worth it.

If you told me six months ago that I’d be this happy right now, I would’ve probably said something like, “sure, keep telling yourself that.”  I didn’t believe that life would ever be bright and happy again.  Now, though, I wake up each day with gratitude in my heart for how far I’ve gotten.  I am so thankful for everyone who has followed my story, sent prayers my way, and supported me through it all.  Who would’ve known that something so dark and so scary could give way to something so beautiful?  I am humbled to be where I am today.

Those tears and those fears on the morning of my surgery would have disappeared immediately if I would have known then how amazing my life would soon become.  I am so undeserving of this wonderful journey, but I am so grateful for the life I’ve been given.

Posted in Amputation and tagged Amputation, Amputation Journey, Amputee, Amputee Life, Ampuversary, Best Hospital, Change, Chronic Pain, Fear, Freedom, Hospital, Journey, Life, Medical, My Amputee Story, My Life, My Story, Perspective, RBKA, Six Months, Surgery on May 25, 2015. 6 Comments
ENCOUNTERING PEOPLE WHO ARE DIFFERENT
The other day, I was in the store when I heard a little girl call out to her mom.  “Mom, come here! Mom! That girl–why does she look–?”  Her mom tried to hush her before she went on.  “Shh.  I’ll explain it to you, but you have to come over here,” she said, leading her daughter to a different area.  When they came back to where I was, the girl and her brother tried to catch another glance at my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> while their mom tried to stop them from staring by offering other things to look at.

I think situations like the one described above come from the desire to not intrude or offend.  We don’t want to say or do the wrong thing, especially around people who are “different.”  It’s totally understandable, but sometimes I think our avoidance is counterproductive.  When I hear people talking about my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> in hushed voices, or pulling their kids away from me to talk about what they think happened, it only magnifies the idea that something is “wrong” with me.  (Side note: I don’t actually think anything is wrong with me, and the world knows how proud I am of my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> leg </object>.  But when situations like this happen, it communicates that idea to others.  The idea that something is wrong and that it shouldn’t be talked about. But it should.)

Everyone is different, but for me personally, I’d rather people just ask about what happened rather than trying to conjure their own explanations.  I am an open book, as I’ve said multiple times.  I’d rather answer questions personally than have people get the wrong impression about my amputation.

People try to avoid awkward conversations and uncomfortable situations.  I think that’s normal.  But there are ways to acknowledge these things without making a bigger deal out of it.  The mother that I described could have simply told her kids that I had a <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> prosthetic leg </object> and let it at that.  She could have said something that would allow her kids to know that disabilities and differences are to be celebrated, not shushed.  Instead of making her children feel like they did something wrong by asking about my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object>, she could have been honest with them.

I am not trying to criticize the mom in the story, because I know that she was probably just trying to be sensitive to my feelings. I get that.  I can be awkward around people who are different sometimes, too.  But I use the story above to show that there are different ways to go about handling situations.  I can’t speak for everyone, but here are some things that I think would be helpful when encountering people with disabilities or people who look/talk/act differently from you:

-Treat people like humans, not problems or disabilities.  Underneath our metal legs and battle scars, we are all humans.  We have emotions, thoughts, and lives just like you.  Treat us like you’d treat anyone else.
–Smile.  A simple, non-condescending smile can go a long way.
-Don’t be afraid of us!  Fake legs, wheelchairs, and machines are not scary monsters. They are simply necessities that help us to live the best life possible.  Don’t fear what you do not know.  Seriously.
–If you are with kids and they ask questions, answer in a positive light.  Don’t shut down their curiosity.  Rather than trying to silence them, give them some information.  “That girl uses a cool leg to walk.  Isn’t it neat?” or “Yes, she has a scar, but isn’t it beautiful?”
–Don’t make assumptions about our stories.  If you want to know what happened, ask.  Don’t try to tell your kids that someone was sick or something if you don’t truly know the story.  In the case of amputation, there are multiple reasons why someone could end up that way.  Some people are born without limbs.  Some were sick, while others had traumatic accidents. Don’t make up stories to explain our differences.
-If you really want to know something, ask politely.  Some people are uncomfortable acknowledging the “elephant in the room,” but the worst that will happen is they will tell you that they’d rather not talk about it.  Trust me, you’re probably not the first person to ask them a question.  Many people are happy to talk about it.  Just don’t be rude with your words.

I am aware that this is an area where people don’t know what to do.  I wish that weren’t the case, since we’re all humans and our level of ability shouldn’t cause such awkwardness, but that’s how it is.  The net time you see someone who is different than you, remember that they have a story.  They have a life.  They are a person who deserves to be respected, and you don’t have to be uncomfortable around them.  When in doubt, choose kindness and don’t make assumptions.  Those two things can go a long way.

Posted in Amputation and tagged Ability, Amputation, Amputee, Amputee Life, Attitude, Awkward, Difference, Disabilities, Encounters with differences, Life, My Story, People with disabilities, Prosthetic, We Are Human on May 21, 2015. 8 Comments
CHANGE & LETTING GO
 IMG_2363For someone who loves to have everything planned out, this season of life has been…well, a bit hectic.  I guess it’s really more than just a season, since my life has been one change after another for the past nine years or so.  It has been a constant journey of trusting that everything will somehow work out, even when I don’t understand what is happening in a given moment.

Just when I start to get settled and comfortable, something happens to change up my plans.  This has been particularly evident lately in my academic life.  I think I know where I’m going and what I want to do, and then–BAM–something changes.  I think that’s pretty normal for college students, though.  Most people change majors more than once, so I don’t feel too abnormal about that.  Many people also change schools…which I also have done.  But I think that part of my identity has been wrapped up in who I wanted to be and what I wanted to do in the future, which is why this newest change in my life has been necessary but difficult.

For the past few years, I have had a plan about my future career goals.  I knew what I wanted to study, looked into different ways to get my degree, and thought everything was good to go.  Friends and family commented on how great of a career choice I had, and how wonderful it was that I would be getting my Master’s degree within the next few years.  Along the way, though, I’ve hit several roadblocks, detours, and signs that maybe there was something else that I was supposed to do.  My dreams were good, but maybe they weren’t the best.

Lately, I’ve been feeling a push to leave my desired major and take a different path.  It’s been a huge topic of discussion and debate, a process of weighing the pros and cons of going with the new plan that I feel led toward.  I’ve done some research, talked to multiple people, and discussed things with the Big Man upstairs.  Although it’s hard to push aside the ideal plans that I had made, it has become more clear that something else is up ahead.  Something that I don’t fully understand right now, but that I hope will make more sense along the way.

As of this week, I’ve decided to let go of my previous plans and go down a different road.  I’m switching majors and hoping to graduate next year rather than in three years.  My identity will no longer be held in my career aspirations.  It’s something that I’m feeling a sense of peace about, so this is the way I am choosing to go.  I don’t know what the future holds in terms of my education and career, but at least I have a start.

Even though I feel peace about my decision, letting go of my plans is not easy.  Sometimes I think that I know what’s best for my life, so I cling to my “perfect” plan.  But in reality, I don’t always know what’s best.  Other people see things that I am blind to.  I feel nudges about taking a different route.  I do not always know the best way to live my life.  Even when it’s challenging, I need to let go of my plans and let Him take charge.  I’m looking forward to seeing how this all plays out in the future.

Posted in My Life and tagged Academic Life, College, Degree, Education, Faith, Future, Hope, Letting Go, Life, Major, My Life, Psychology, School, Trust on May 18, 2015. 1 Comment
DONE WITH PT!
Guess what happened yesterday?  Well, if you’ve read the title, then you know…I had my last day of Physical Therapy!  Even though I’m going to miss going over to the hospital on a regular basis, I’m happy that I am well enough to leave behind the days of multiple appointments per week.

It’s so encouraging to look back and see how far I’ve come in the past 3 months or so since I received my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> leg </object> and began PT.  When I started therapy in February, I was still using both crutches.  I did not trust my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> at all and I had a terrible limp.  My knee wasn’t able to fully extend because of the contracture that had been present for so long.  I occasionally tried to leave the crutches behind, but I always felt the need to go back to them for safety and stability.  I remember my therapist telling me that it would take some time before I was able to walk unassisted.  I so desperately wanted to jump ahead and be walking and running freely, but I knew that there was a process that I needed to go through first.

Once I finally ditched the crutches about a month after starting therapy, I moved to a cane.  I didn’t like that very much, mostly because it made me feel too old.  I used the cane occasionally, but tried to limp around without it.  I still had some strengthening to do, but it was a huge step to leave the crutches behind.

Finally, after deciding that my cane-using days were over, I began walking unassisted…all the time.  My PT wasn’t very big into that idea at first because she knew that I still had some weakness that we needed to take care of, so I still used the cane in our sessions.  Gradually, I noticed that my trust in my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> increased and my limp decreased.

Now, I only have a slight limp that most people probably don’t notice.  Sure, it gets worse when I’m tired or in pain, but for the most part, my muscles are strong and my body is stable.  Oh, and I’ve regained almost all of the range of motion in my knee, which is a HUGE deal!  I’m able to walk, jog, hike, canoe, go to the beach…basically, I’m free to do whatever I want!  I have to wait a few months before I can talk to my doctor about getting a running leg, which I would love to have, and I might see about getting a swimming leg in the future.  I’m determined to enjoy life and push through as many so-called limits as possible!

Many thanks go out to the therapists at St. Joe’s, especially my PT, Jenna.  Without her, I wouldn’t have gotten this far.  She helped me overcome my challenges, one wobbly step at a time.  It wasn’t always easy, but every difficult session showed me how strong and capable my body is.  I am so, so grateful to have my life back.  Not a day goes by that I don’t think about how incredible it is that I am finally walking, <object value = "car" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> driving </object>, and in less pain than I have been in years.  I say it all the time, but life is good. And I am grateful.

Now, if you’ll excuse me, I need to start figuring out what to do with all this free time now that I have less appointments!  Haha, just kidding…my life is busy enough and my schedule is already filling up again :)  Thanks for stopping by!

Posted in Amputation and tagged Amputee, Amputee Life, Amputee Rehab, Health, Hospital, Journey, Leg Amputee, Medical, My Life, My Story, Physical Rehab, Physical Therapy, PT, RBKA, Rehab, Therapy on May 15, 2015. 10 Comments
MOTHER’S DAY
 IMG_0976Happy Mother’s Day to all the wonderful moms, moms-to-be, and people who take on the role of a mom out there! It takes a special person to be a great mom. I am thankful to have an incredible mom who blesses me on a daily basis, and I could never thank her enough for all that she does for my family.

To those out there who struggle with this holiday for whatever reason, know that I am thinking about you especially today. I know people who have broken relationships or who are desperate to become a mom, and I am thinking about those brave women who have to watch as everyone else celebrates and changes their Facebook profile photos or posts pictures of their mom on Instagram. I’m sure days like today only add salt to the wounds, but I hope and pray that better days are ahead and the holiday will soon be a reason for joy.

I believe that my mom deserves an extra bit of recognition today.  It takes a fierce momma to deal with a kid who has a chronic illness.  I don’t think she looked at my face when I was born and envisioned countless nights on tiny hospital beds or endless days filled with worry. She never planned on having to watch as her daughter screamed bloody murder while she was forced to stand there, unable to help. I’m pretty sure she never imagined she’d be sending her child across the country to the middle of the desert at age 15, to Nashville at age 16, or to Cleveland multiple times, all for lengthy stays with limited contact. In her dreams about becoming a mom, I’m positive that RSD, eating disorders, or amputation never crossed her mind. She never signed up for any of this, and yet, that’s what she’s had to deal with.

My mom has handled all of my issues with such love and grace. She has dealt with horrible doctors, crappy sleeping situations, distance from her family and other kids, and messy situations…all for me. She flew me all the way to Arizona and had the courage to walk away from me, knowing that leaving her daughter in this unfamiliar place was what was necessary to save my life. When that place did its job as being “life support” temporarily but failed in the long run, she once again took me to a new state and said goodbye with tears in her eyes. It’s not in a (good) mother’s nature to be willing to send her children away, but she did it because she knew that that was what I needed. She sacrificed her own pain and heartache for the possibility that I would have a better life.

When I was told that I needed to have my leg amputated, my mom stood beside me.  She is the one who insisted that my doctor’s appointment be moved up to an earlier date, and without that, I very well could have died from the infection that was invading my body.  She agreed to support me in my decision to make it a positive experience.  I can’t imagine that it’s easy to watch your daughter being wheeled into an Operating Room, knowing that she’ll come out with a missing limb, but she let the doctors do their job.  She’s been the best amputee momma out there, supporting me through it all.

I can’t even imagine the amount of time my mom has spent praying for me, crying for me, and worrying about me. She had to deal with my anger and harsh words toward her when I was writhing in pain, both physically and emotionally. She had to listen as I screamed and shouted about how much I wished I were dead, and she often had to go against my own (unhealthy) wishes because she knew what was best for me.

My mom has been through so much but she continues to embrace life with a smile. Rather than giving up when things got tough, she pressed on and has served as an encouragement and inspiration to those around her. She always reminds me how much I am loved and how proud she is to be my mom, even when I’ve put her through hell and back. I will never fully fathom how strong she is and the deepness of her love and sacrifice for my family.

Happy Mother’s Day, Momma. I look forward to so many more memories and fun times together in the future. Keep up the good work, because you are one outstanding woman.  <3

Posted in My Life and tagged Mom, Mother, Mother's Day, Thanks Mom on May 10, 2015. 10 Comments
FLYING AS AN AMPUTEE
Processed with MoldivLast week, I took a trip to Delaware to spend some time with my brother and our awesome family friends.  It was the first time that I had flown since my amputation, so I wasn’t completely sure what to expect.  With the heightened security these days, I wondered if I’d be hassled about my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object>.

We arrived at the airport in the evening, so things were relatively empty.  I was wearing <object value = "shorts" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> shorts </object> so that the TSA agents could easily identify me as an amputee.  (I figured that’d be better than sliding through the metal detector and beeping.)  When one of the workers noticed my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object>, she told me to step into the full-body scanner.  She was very friendly, commenting on my <object value = "shoes" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> sparkly shoes </object> (which she let me keep on) and asking about my travel adventures.  After a few swipes of a warm cloth over my hands and <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> prosthetic leg </object> to check for anything suspicious, I was cleared to go to my gate.

It was so nice to travel without crutches for the first time in years.  I used to struggle with getting on the plane and finding a spot for my aluminum sidekicks.  This time, it was just me and my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object>, which was securely fastened to my body.  I opted to forego pre boarding since I consider myself to be as able-bodied as anyone else.  When our zone was called, we headed to our seats and sat down.

I was very happy with how smoothly things went during my trip.  After having some not-so-pleasant flying experiences in the past, this felt like a breeze.  The flight attendants played movie trivia with us while we waited to depart, and the flight was comfortable.

On the way home, security was more strict (I had to take off my <object value = "shoes" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> shoes </object>, which is a pain…but that’s okay) but I didn’t have too many issues.  I was once again scanned, swiped, and sent on my way.  I had no problems getting to my gate or boarding the plane.

If you’re flying as an amputee, here are some tips that I think helped my experience:

-Wear shorts/short-sleeved shirts (depending on where your amputation happened) so that you can be easily identified as an amputee.  It’s much better than making the metal detector go crazy!  Plus, it is easier for the TSA agents to access your prosthetic (if you have one) so that they can test it for any harmful substances.
-Wear shoes that are easy to remove.  If you are a lower limb amputee with a prosthetic leg such as myself, you may have to take off your shoes.  It’s better to wear comfortable shoes that you can quickly take on and off.
-If you have the option, don’t wear too many socks.  Your limbs tend to swell a bit while flying, so if you have too many socks on your limb, you may feel uncomfortable tightness.
-Relax and enjoy your time!

I love to travel, and it is such a relief to know that flying as an amputee isn’t as complicated as I once thought.  I look forward to future adventures now that I am confident in both my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> and my ability to travel without major issues!

Posted in Amputation, Uncategorized and tagged Adventure, Amputation, Amputee, Amputee Air Travel, Amputee Travel, Flying as an amputee, Flying with a prosthesis, Life, My Life, Prosthetic, Travel, TSA on May 9, 2015. 2 Comments
JUST FOR TODAY
 IMG_1188Each day gives us 24 hours.  Sometimes we wish for more time to get things done, but there are other times when we aren’t even sure if we can make it through the day without a breakdown.  At least that’s how it is for me.  But regardless of what happens, each day only has 24 hours.

At a recent meeting that I attended, someone shared about the 5 principles of Reiki.  Aside from doing some quick research on this practice when I was talked into trying it while in the hospital a few years back, I didn’t know much about it.  I still don’t, really, and I didn’t find it to be an effective healing technique in my personal situation.  Regardless of the ins and outs of Reiki, I appreciated the content of the 5 principles that were shared:

Just for today, I will not anger.
Just for today, I will not worry.
Just for today, I will be honest.
Just for today, I will be grateful.
Just for today, I will be compassionate toward myself and others.

As I’ve gone through the past few weeks, I have reflected on these principles.  Am I refraining from anger?  Am I allowing my faith to be bigger than my fear?  Am I being honest?  Am I taking time to show my gratitude and appreciation, even for the little things?  Am I giving myself the grace that I need and being compassionate toward others?  It’s good to be mindful of our actions so that we know how to improve.

I believe that these are five important things that can be difficult at times, but really have the power to change our mindset.  By  focusing on one day at a time, they don’t seem as tough to accomplish.  Just for today, you can keep going.  Just for today, you can choose to be positive.  Just for today, you can remember that there is life to be lived.  Tomorrow has its own worries, but just for today, you can handle what’s in front of you.  And with each new day, you can start fresh with the idea that something wonderful is going to happen.  Even the darkest moments can have glimmers of light if you take the time to look closely and choose to see things through eyes of gratitude and positivity.  Just for today…you can be strong and hold on.

Posted in My Life and tagged Compassion, Gratitude, Honesty, Hope, Life, Mindfulness, Mindset, My Life, Peace, Positive, Principles of Reiki, Reiki, Thoughts, Today on May 3, 2015. 5 Comments
LIMB LOSS AWARENESS MONTH
 Processed with MoldivHow is it almost May?!  Before time slips away any faster, I figured I should squeeze in a post about why April is an important month.  Do you know what’s special about this month of the year?  (Well, besides the birds chirping, warmer temperatures, and the anticipation of summer.)  In case you haven’t already caught on from my post title and the featured image, April is Limb Loss Awareness Month!

Last April, I had no clue that it was such a significant month for awareness.  Amputation, in my mind, was never going to become a personal experience.  But now that I’m an amputee?  I see April as a way to celebrate life and spread awareness about taking care of your limbs so you don’t have to go through the terrifying wonderful process of joining the amputee club.

Here’s the deal: chances are, you’ll never even have to think about becoming an amputee.  I mean, most people make it through life with all their limbs intact.  However, bodies are funny and life is strange, and you never know when you or a loved one may become a potential amputee.

Each day, more than 500 Americans become amputees. (Statistic from the Amputee Coalition)  That seems like a lot, right?  To me it does.  There are numerous causes for peoples’ amputations, some which are preventable.  Regardless of the cause, with so many people becoming amputees daily, awareness about amputation is important.

Why is awareness important?  Well, first of all, many people do not know how to react to amputees.  Parents tell their kids not to stare.  People shy away from the subject.  Sometimes the fact that someone is different brings up questions or awkwardness and people don’t know how what to do.  Now that I am on the other side of things, I realize that each amputee has been on a unique journey to get to where they are.  Some want to forget that it ever happened, while others are completely fine with their amputation.  Either way, amputees should be treated like the normal human beings that they (we) are.  We’re not aliens or robots just because we may have metal limbs!  Our differences don’t have to be scary.

Awareness is also important because many times, amputation can be prevented with proper care.  We’re only given one body while we’re here on this earth, so it is critical that we take care of ourselves.  Making positive lifestyle choices can help avoid health problems.  Becoming aware of changes in our bodies is also important so that issues can be resolved before they spiral out of control.  Take me for example.  If I would’ve gone to the doctor when I first noticed signs of my limb breaking down instead of waiting until things became irreversible, then I might not have ended up where I am today.  My fear of doctors kept me from seeking help, but now I know that the right doctors will do anything they can to make sure their patients’ needs are taken care of.

I am a proud amputee and I am grateful for how far I’ve come since my surgery five months ago.  I hope that as awareness increases, my fellow amputees will realize that they are not alone.  Amputation doesn’t have to mean isolation or the end of a happy, fulfilling life.  I also hope that non-amputees will realize that amputees are just like anybody else, and there’s no need to fear what you don’t understand.  If you have any questions about the amputee life, know that you can always ask me!  I love telling people about my journey and spreading awareness about amputation.

As I heard many times this weekend as I sat in the audience of Shrek, Jr., what makes us special makes us strong.  Let’s embrace our differences and celebrate life together.

Posted in Amputation and tagged Amputation, Amputee, Amputee Awareness, Amputee Coalition, Amputee Life, Awareness, Health, Healthy, Humans, Life, Limb Loss Awareness, Living, Medical on April 27, 2015. 2 Comments
5 MONTHS & A 5K!
Five months ago today, I was sleeping in my hospital room after having my leg amputated.  My doctors weren’t sure how well I would recover from surgery.  Would I walk again?  Surely I’d be in pain, they thought.  My Leg Guy didn’t know if I’d be able to wear a prosthesis because of my issues with sensitivity.  My medical team all thought that maybe I’d walk, but they weren’t sure if I’d be able to do more than that.

This morning, exactly 5 months after surgery, my dad and I drove to the hospital where my leg was removed.  This time, instead of being in a boring hospital gown with tubes hanging from my body, I was sporting a snazzy <object value = "shirt" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> "Join Me" shirt </object> and a <object value = "race bib" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> race bib </object>.  In place of my old bandages that were once wrapped around my limb, I was proudly showing off my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> new leg </object>.  On the campus of the hospital where I once broke down sobbing over the idea of losing my leg, I was preparing to participate in a 5K.

My dad and I were joined by our awesome friends who have walked alongside me during the past few years of my crazy journey.  It was great to have Dee and her kids with us because they have been so encouraging to me, both before and after my surgery.  I watch the kids every week, and they were a big reason why I was motivated to get up and walk again–I wanted to be able to play outside and do fun things with them!  It felt like things were coming around full circle–after going through the darkest storm, the clouds had finally cleared and I was enjoying freedom while being surrounded by incredible people.

Processed with Moldiv
                     {Together we will run}

After doing our warmups and laughing at how many times the instructor talked about ankle mobility, noting the fact that I can’t exactly move my right ankle on my own, we waved to the drone in the air and began the race.  It was hard for me to believe that I was actually participating in a 5K.  I did one a few years ago, but I figured that with my health issues, that would be the one and only race I’d ever be able to do.  I’m glad that I can now add another race to the list, with hopes of doing many more in the future.  My <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> isn’t exactly built for running (I get to talk to my Leg Guy and doctor about getting one of those in September), so most of the time was spent walking.  I tried to jog a bit but I think it looked more like a beginner’s Irish jig than a graceful run.  That’s okay, though, because I was just happy to be moving!

Never in my wildest dreams did I imagine that I’d be doing this well right now.  Before surgery, I had gone through a bit of an acceptance phase when I realized that I probably wouldn’t get better.  People said I’d never walk again, which meant that running was far out of the realm of possibilities.  Never say never, right?  Today, as I ran across the finish line, I celebrated the fact that I was able to finally prove them wrong.  I am hoping that this is just the beginning of a new, active lifestyle.  I’m grateful for where I am right now and I am trying to enjoy every moment, knowing all too well how things can change suddenly.  (Of course, I’m not expecting anything bad to happen, but I plan on living my life to the fullest as long as I can.)

A 5K may not seem like a big deal, but for the girl who spent 2.5 years on crutches, it was a miracle. Thanks for the fun, St. Joe’s! :)

Posted in Amputation, My Life and tagged 5K, Active, Amputation, Amputation Journey, Amputee, Amputee Life, Best Hospital, Family, Freedom, Friends, Fun, Hospital, Joy, Life, My Life, Prosthesis, Race, Run, Saint Joseph Mercy, SJMHS, SJMHS Wellness 5K, Walk on April 25, 2015. 13 Comments
WHO’S ON MY TEAM?
When you become an amputee, you are basically forced to interact with several medical professionals.  Besides the obvious people who are there when your surgery first happens, you develop a team of people who have different roles in your care after you go home.  I find myself at the hospital at least twice a week because of all the appointments I get to go to.  Soon, the frequency of my visits will lower, but for now I am enjoying the time I get to spend at St. Joe’s.

So…who’s on my post-op care team?  I’ve gotten some questions about how my appointments have been going, and when/where they happen.  Here are some of the amazing people who have helped me get to where I am today:

Vascular Surgeon (AKA Dr. Hero) : He’s the one who chopped my leg off.  Before surgery, I was in his office multiple times per week to see a wonderful nurse for dressing changes.  Now, my visits are more spread out–in fact, the next time I see him won’t be until July!  I still see him and the people from his office sometimes when I’m roaming around the hospital, but that’s just to say hello.

Physical Medicine Doctor :  I don’t see this doctor much, but he is the one who signs the paperwork when I’m ready to get a new leg.  I see him at Amputee Clinic once every few months.  We chat for a few minutes and he checks my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> leg </object> out to make sure everything is going well.

Leg Guy (Or in technical terms, prosthetist) : I spend the most time with my Leg Guy and my Physical Therapist these days.  My Leg Guy makes adjustments to my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> and casts me for new sockets when needed.  I’m getting my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> laminated in a few weeks, so it’ll look better than it does right now.  I mean, random lines and circles made in permanent marker all over my <object value = "prosthetic leg" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> leg </object> are cool and all, but I’m looking forward to my new design :)

Physical Therapist: PT is loads of fun. Really, it is! It’s so exciting to look at how much progress I’ve made each week. I see my Physical Therapist twice a week, and we do a lot of strengthening exercises (leg press, resistance bands, etc) among other things. We are currently working hard to get rid of my limp, which means my muscles need to get stronger!  I’ve met most of my goals, so I only have a few PT visits left.  I’ll still have to do my exercises at home, but I won’t have to wake up early for appointments anymore.

Friends and Family: Okay, so this doesn’t really fit into the medical team category, but you are all so amazing.  I would not be where I am today without the love and support of my friends and family.  It is so encouraging to know that I have people on my side so I’m not going through all of this alone.  Thank you to each and every one of you!

I feel like I’m missing people, but maybe not.  I am so thankful to have an incredible team of people walking alongside me on this fun and wild journey.  There’s your little glimpse into the life of Rachel for the day :)

Posted in Amputation, Uncategorized and tagged Amputation, Amputee, Amputee Life, Doctor, Family, Friends, Hospital, Leg Guy, Life, Medical, Medical Journey, My Life, Physical Therapist, Post Op, Prosthetic, Prosthetist, PT, Surgeon, Surgery, Vascular Surgeon on April 21, 2015. 2 Comments

