date: 6/9/2015
site: http://theboslife.blogspot.com/2015/04/my-26th-surprise.html

my 26th! a surprise!
My 26th birthday landed on a Monday this year and as a result Fernando claimed he wanted to go out on a date the Saturday before to celebrate. What was really happening, unbeknownst to me was the planning of a surprise birthday party!

My friend Ana contacted Fernando and asked if he thought it was a good idea to plan a surprise party for my birthday. He of course said yes and they went to planning. Ana and Juan generously hosted the party!

First we had dinner at our <object value = "house" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> house </object> with Nonna, Nonno, Laura and Svet. Then Laura and Svet claimed they needed to get going and left right after dinner was over. Shortly after Fernando and I went on our way with (what I thought was) our plans for dessert. Nonno and Nonna stayed to babysit the girls and we headed out. 

When we got in the car Fernando told me I needed to put my <object value = "scarf" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> scarf </object> over my eyes and cover them all the way to our destination. He said he wanted the dessert place we were going to be a surprise. At this point I still wasn't suspicious. This is the kind of stuff Fernando does randomly so I definitely didn't think it was a surprise party!  

When we pulled up to the place and Fernando said "okay, we're here!" I knew something was up. It was obvious he pulled into a driveway and not a restaurant parking lot. Then he opened up a door (which was obviously to someone's home) and had me walk in. When I took off the <object value = "scarf" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> scarf </object> we were in Ana's house! There were a bunch of my friends there saying "surprise." And I most definitely was surprised! 

Laura and Svet were supposed to be there when we showed up but they came shortly after. They walked in with wine to share and some special chocolates for me (to not share;)! They also had the birthday cake and some cheese, crackers and fruit which Fernando went out to grab earlier in the day without me knowing it! He got my favorite lemon cake from Nantucket Grill with the sweetest message on it! 

I guess when Laura and Svet left our <object value = "house" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> house </object> they grabbed the cake and other things from the trunk of Fernando's car since they were supposed to show up at the party before us. (They needed to stop for wine on the way so that's why we ended up beating them there.) Either way all of the goodies got there and there was a great group of people there to celebrate! 

This was my first surprise birthday party! I felt so blessed to have such a great friend to think of/plan/host the party, an amazing husband to pull off all the last minute details and such great family and friends to celebrate with! 
  
 Laura is the only lady missing from this <object value = "picture" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> picture </object>!! (We took it after she left)
(And all of these lovely lady's husbands/fiancés were there as well!)

Now on to my actual birthday! 


 Since we had already celebrated my birthday plenty over the weekend I figured that was it as far as presents went... so I was surprised to find this <object value = "book" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> book </object> wrapped in a bow with a <object value = "note" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> sweet note </object> from Fernando the morning of my birthday! I had told him I wanted this book back in January but had all but forgotten about it. I have heard great things about it and am excited to start reading it! 


My coffee and treat c/o Nonna and Nonno babysitting!

About mid morning on my birthday Nonna called me and said she scheduled a facial for me at 1pm. She then showed up with Nonno to watch the girls so I could go enjoy my facial. She handed me 10 bucks and said "this is for the tip" and then another 10 and said "this is for a fancy coffee and I don't want to see you back here before 4." Aka: what every mother of young children wants to hear.

I had never gotten a facial so this was a special experience. It was amazing!

(On the form you fill out before getting a facial it asks if you've ever had a facial before. The lady giving the facial read on the form that this was my first and she asked me "you've never had a facial before?!?" and looked at me like I had 3 heads. It was as if I told her I've never had chocolate before.)


My sweet friend Ashley sent me a birthday package! I was so surprised with the present and how thoughtful each item was. She sent all these adorable things- plus the ones in the <object value = "bags" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> cute bags </object> are homemade granola and homemade chocolate fudge!
So delicious and so thoughtful! Thanks again Ash!


