Real Life Minimalists: Conrad
By miss minimalist | 11 comments
Pin It
Every Monday I post Real Life Minimalists, a profile of one of my readers in their own words. If you’d like to participate, click here for details.

This week, Conrad tells us about the pared-down lifestyle he and his wife enjoy aboard their boat. I love how he describes time as “the great equalizer,” and shares how his minimalism helps him make the most of it. Please visit his blog to learn more.

Conrad writes:

Conrad and Roxanne
Conrad and Roxanne
Living in a country where bigger is synonymous with better, being a minimalist is a title my wife and I often kept to ourselves. Even the coolest slogans encourage upsizing: “Go Big or Go Home”, “Everything is Bigger in Texas”, “Dream Big”, “Speak Softly and Carry a Big Stick.”

Becoming a minimalist seemed like a step in the wrong direction.

But taking steps to minimalize our possessions allowed us to maximize our quality of life. Three years ago we quit our jobs, sold our house, furniture, cars and 99% of our possessions. We then bought a <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> boat </object> (we paid cash, no more debt for us) and moved aboard.

Now we live in some of the most picturesque marinas surrounded by million dollar views and million dollar homes. The marina’s supply the internet access, pay for the <object value = "water" id = "1" type = "perm" agreement = "S"> water </object>, provide for garbage service and lease us a <object value = "parking slip" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> slip </object> to park our <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> boat </object> all for under $300 per month.

Our <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> 49′ motor yacht </object> (purchase price, less than $50,000) became the perfect <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> minimalist home </object> for us. There is no need to outfit it with furniture, the <object value = "furniture" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> furniture </object> is already built into the <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> boat </object>. When we moved aboard it was like walking into a furnished home. The <object value = "couches" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> couches </object>, <object value = "end tables" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> end tables </object>, <object value = "lamps" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> lamps </object>, <object value = "beds" id = "6" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> beds </object>, <object value = "chest of drawers" id = "7" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> chest of drawers </object> were already there. The couple we bought the <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> boat </object> from even left all of the <object value = "pots" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> pots </object>, <object value = "pans" id = "9" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> pans </object>, <object value = "dishes" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> dishes </object> and <object value = "silverware" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> silverware </object>. We literally could have moved our <object value = "clothes" id = "12" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> clothes </object> and <object value = "laptops" id = "13" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> laptops </object> aboard and been 95% moved in.

Then we created an internet consulting business. Since our bills were very minimal we didn’t need to make a lot of money (less than $2,000/month at first). My previous job’s hour long morning commute had transformed into a 20 foot walk, usually still wearing my <object value = "pajamas" id = "14" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> pajamas </object> and sipping on hot coffee. We have no need for two cars because we work from the <object value = "boat" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EM"> boat </object>. We don’t drive much so we don’t spend much on gas. The <object value = "car" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> tires </object> need changing less often and we only need to pay insurance on one <object value = "car" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> car </object>. It’s a real eye opener when you add up all of the expenses that are directly associated to having a job.

Though we make half the money of our previous lives we have double the disposable income. But where we really go big with being minimalist is the life experiences that we can now enjoy. We no longer need to work 40 or 50 hours per week. Often times I am finished working by noon and I take off even earlier on Fridays. My wife and I have spent our extra time visiting coastal cities, learning to play the <object value = "guitar" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SM"> guitar </object>, finishing her college degree, learning to speak Spanish, writing books, taking the <object value = "dogs" id = "17" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> dogs </object> on long walks and learning the tango. Daily we literally have hours to use as we please.

Time, to me, is the only commodity in life that has real value. It’s the great equalizer and the most democratic of all things. It doesn’t matter if you are rich or poor, famous or anonymous, black or white, fat or thin or any other differentiator that exists in the world. We all wake up each day with the same amount of time. We all have 24 hours to spend as we see fit.

The question my wife and I asked ourselves 3 years ago was, “Do we really want to spend all of our time at work so we can buy things we don’t really need?”

Yeah we’re minimalist when it comes to possessions but when it comes to getting the most out of life, we’re maximalist!

If you’re interested in our whole story, check out our <object value = "book" id = "18" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> book </object>, “Own Less & Live More: a sailing adventure that takes you from the cubicle to Key West.”

{If you’d like to learn more about minimalist living, please consider reading my <object value = "book" id = "18" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "SEM"> book </object>, The Joy of Less, A Minimalist Living Guide, or subscribing to my RSS feed.}





