Date: 5/13/2015
Page: http://theinspiredroom.net/

When we first moved into our <object value = "house" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> house </object>, our <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> backyard </object> was a <object value = "house" id = "0" type = "perm" agreement = "M"> typical new construction home </object> on barren land. No trees, no plants, no landscaping. We had weeds and rocks for <object value = "soil" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> soil </object>, and that was it. After living in <object value = "old homes" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> old homes </object> with established landscaping to work with, our <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> sad little backyard </object> was a bit depressing. I love to design small garden areas but since our <object value = "soil" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> soil </object> was filled with rocks, planting was nearly impossible. Any time I had the urge to plant something, it was a big ordeal. I knew I was going to have to enjoy the small improvements we could make each year since a professionally landscaped backyard was not in our plans.

The <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> yard </object> didn’t have any structure at all to begin with, so last year we focused on adding shape, interest and function by creating a <object value = "patio" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> pea gravel patio </object> patio for our <object value = "fire pit" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> fire pit </object>, a <object value = "walkway" id = "6" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> flagstone walkway </object>, and designated some planting areas.

By dividing our <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> backyard </object> into four zones, we felt like we could make the most of our space and even almost visualize it eventually being a charming and useful <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> backyard </object>! The designated zones also help us to know where to focus our time and improvements! This summer we are really excited to be laying a <object value = "patio" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> flagstone patio </object> for our <object value = "table" id = "7" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> table </object> and adding more <object value = "plants" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> plants </object> and <object value = "trees" id = "9" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> trees </object>.

While it will be many years before our <object value = "landscape" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "MS"> landscape </object> is as full and lush as I dream it will be, it helps me to feel like I’m making progress when I zero in on these little areas I can improve right now. It’s easy for me to get overwhelmed by the big picture, so it’s nice and definitely encouraging to see each little area coming along! One thing I tend to struggle with when I do projects around the <object value = "house" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> house </object> or <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> yard </object> is FOCUS. I’m all over the map sometimes, doing a little bit here and a little bit there. But since I know concentrated FOCUS is what can quickly transform little uneventful areas into inspiring spaces, I really have been trying hard to grow in my ability to stick with improving one corner at a time until it feels more complete.

This little spot has been in progress for awhile, but recently I did a little spring clean up, planted a few <object value = "pots" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> pots </object> and <object value = "plants" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> plants </object> and set up a <object value = "Adirondack chair " id = "12" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> charming folding Trex Adirondack chair </object> and <object value = "end table" id = "13" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "MS"> end table </object> near my <object value = "spool table" id = "14" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement ="EMS"> recycled spool table </object> (you can find the all weather patio furniture from Trex). I’m absolutely in love with Adirondack chairs (see this post for some more inspiration!) and this <object value = "Adirondack chair" id = "12" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> one </object> is so adorable and low maintenance, too! Perfect for our Northwest weather.

When we look back at the <object value = "photo" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement ="ES"> before photo </object> (above) of where this area all started and see how far we’ve come, we are more determined than ever to keep on giving each corner of our <object value = "backyard" id = "1" type = "perm" agreement = "EMS"> yard </object> a little more love every year.

A little landscaping, some <object value = "pots" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> cute pots </object> and <object value = "plants" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> plants </object>, a few <object value = "accessories" id = "16" type = "perm" agreement = "EM"> accessories </object> and <object value = "furniture" id = "17" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> charming furniture </object> made a world of difference!

Do you have a sad backyard corner you could improve this Spring?

The post was created in partnership with Trex. As always, my opinions are my own.