Date: 5/13/2015
Site: http://jazzabellesdiary.blogspot.com/

SATURDAY, 9 MAY 2015
life lately...

It's been a while since I've posted on here, over the last year I really have stepped back from my <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> blog </object> a little, more so in the last six months. Why? I've just not been feeling that inspired with it - the more I try to focus on my <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> blog </object> the more I compare myself, my <object value = "camera" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "em"> photography </object> and writing skills to others, which is unnecessarily bringing me down. And let's be honest, I work Monday - Friday so at the weekend sometimes all I want to do is be lazy and spend time with my boyfriend and family. I absolutely love my <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> blog </object> and what having it has done for me, but right now I'm doing what I can to keep my happiness levels up. And let me tell you, I really am pretty happy...

Life - Things in my life have been going pretty well this year, I've been feeling so content. I've started to get the itch to move out into my own home (hello, endless interior shopping!) and settling down a little, but I'm not in too much of a rush and I know that things will happen at the right time for me. I've reached a milestone on my <object value = "savings" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> savings </object> and I've been making the most of the time I spend with my family, which are two of my priorities at the moment. 
Love - If you haven't worked it out from my <object value = "Twitter" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> Twitter </object> and <object value = "Instagram" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> Instagram </object> yet, I've fallen in love for the first time with the most amazin' guy. I never believed it when people would say "you'll meet someone when you least expect it", but in this case it certainly was true. I'm a pretty emotional and sentimental person so I won't ramble on for too long, but being in love and knowing that I'm with someone who loves me for who I am has made me feel so overwhelmed with happiness. Even my manager has said that when she looks at me she can see heart emojis above my head, haha! 
Work - I can't believe that I've been in my new job for five months already! Saying that sometimes it feels like longer. It's all been quite a learning curve for me, but I'm really proud of my career progress over the last 3 years. Going from a sales assistant to a visual merchandiser then the Flagship Marketing and Events Assistant at Cath Kidston, before moving to Tatty Devine to become their Marketing Executive, dabbling as a stylist in between. All of this without going to university shows it is possible, and even better? I have no debts to pay off! 
Well-being -  Since I wrote my <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> 'flaws and all' blog post </object> back in October, things have remained pretty similar. I've been taking little steps to improve my confidence, complexion, health and fitness, and besides two little blips since then (thanks to the pill and anxiety), things have been lookin' good. I've been <object value = "bed" id = "5" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> getting earlier nights </object>, making time to <object value = "books" id = "6" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> read </object>, eating more <object value = "fruit" id = "7" type = "temp" agreement = "s"> fruit </object> and <object value = "vegetables" id = "8" type = "temp" agreement = "s"> veg </object>, not working from <object value = "home" id = "9" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "em"> home </object> and generally just trying to keep positive. 

This <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> post </object> is a little bit different for me, but it's something I just had the urge to write, so I do hope you liked it! I don't know how often I'll be <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> blogging </object> in the near future, but you can always find me posting away on <object value = "Twitter" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> Twitter </object>, <object value = "Instagram" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> Instagram </object> and <object value = "Facebook" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> Facebook </object>. I'll chat to y'all soon. Love, Jazz.  
POSTED BY JAZMINE ROCKS @ JAZZABELLE'S DIARY AT 17:19 18 COMMENTS: 
FRIDAY, 3 APRIL 2015
short & sweet.

Why hello, just a short and sweet <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> post </object> from me today! I'm currently cosied up on the <object value = "sofa" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> sofa </object> feelin' very happy, as today marks the start of ten days I have off work! It's been a long few months, so I'm super excited to spend some time with my family in Bournemouth, sleep in and catch up on general life admin. I plan to put together a little 'life lately' post soon so I can update y'all up on just what has been going on in my life (and quite a few lovely things have happened recently, I have to say!), so do look out for that. 
Anyway, to the <object value = "clothes" id = "12" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> outfit </object>... Following on from my <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> last outfit post </object>, this look was also shot by the lovely Amber on a chilly day in February. This <object value = "dress" id = "13" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> dress </object> has become my go to outfit as of late - it's super flattering for my shape as it nips in at the waist (giving me the illusion of hips, wahey!) and the length is just perfect. Teamed with my <object value = "boots" id = "14" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> extra sassy knee high boots </object> and a <object value = "fedora" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> classic fedora </object>, this combo certainly did make me feel fancy enough for my Chelsea surroundings. Love Jazz.  
POSTED BY JAZMINE ROCKS @ JAZZABELLE'S DIARY AT 19:29 34 COMMENTS: