Date: 6/9/2015
Page: http://lifeonwilliemaelane.blogspot.com/2015/03/mobile-home-kitchen-remodel-update.html

 Birthday Fun!
Happy Birthday.....to ME!
And Just Like That...It's Over!
A Blissful Weekend
Restoring My Soul
Sunday, March 22, 2015
<object value = "mobile home" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> Mobile Home </object> <object value = "kitchen" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> Kitchen </object> Remodel Update
Hello friends! I wanted to give you a quick update on the progress of the <object value = "kitchen" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> kitchen </object> remodel. We have been busy over the past few days. The hubby took off Thursday and Friday to work on it so we were able to get a lot done. Friday was spent at the hardware store, Lowes, Home Depot, and back at Lowes. I am beginning to feel like those stores are my home away from <object value = "mobile home" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> home </object>...lol! By the way, if you have an Ace Hardware nearby, they have Clark & Kensington and Valspar sample size cans of <object value = "paint" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> paint </object> for $0.99 each which is a great deal. There is a limit of four, but I was able to get 12 with three transactions since the guys know my hubby so well. :) I got some <object value = "paint" id = "2" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> pretty colors </object> to add to my craft stash for future projects. I think the offer is all month long. 

I managed to make a pretty tasty supper tonight. we are tired of sandwiches, frozen pizza, and fast food! I made a sandwich we love...it has Applewood bacon, turkey, Muenster cheese, chipotle mayo, fresh guacamole, and tomato on a toasted Kaiser bun. Served with some sweet tea and kettle chips, it was a tasty supper!

Anywho, let me show you what we have been up to! 

You can see the wall color here. It is painted the same color as my <object value = "dining room" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> dining </object> and <object value = "living room" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> living rooms </object>. It is a very nice neutral color and blends with everything. 

Here are some of the <object value = "cabinets" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> upper cabinets </object> installed. Looking good!

All the <object value = "cabinets" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> uppers </object> installed here except the one that goes over the <object value = "fridge" id = "6" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> fridge </object> that we have to order since they don't stock the size we need.

We still have to put the <object value = "range hood" id = "7" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> new range hood </object> up and finish some trim and of course the <object value = "counters" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> counter tops </object> on this side.

Here is from across the room from my new wall that we built. It will have a <object value = "bar top" id = "9" type = "perm" agreement = "E"> raised bar top </object> on it made from old lumber my grandpa cut years ago. 

Here's a better <object value = "photo" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "S"> shot </object> of that wall. My <object value = "kitchen" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> kitchen </object> is larger now since we extended it out into the <object value = "dining room" id = "3" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> dining room </object> about 2 feet. I can't believe how much bigger it feels!Please excuse the <object value = "tools" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "MS"> tools </object> and mess everywhere and the <object value = "lights" id = "12" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> dangling lights </object>. I have all my <object value = "light fixtures" id = "13" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> new light fixtures </object> but we won't install them until all the construction is done. Don't want to risk them getting broken. There will be <object value = "shelves" id = "14" type = "perm" agreement = "M"> open shelves </object> on the sides of the window.

Here's another <object value = "photo" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> shot </object>. The trim in the corner has been finished since this <object value = "photo" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> photo </object> was taken. The plastic was still on the <object value = "dishwasher" id = "15" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> dishwasher </object> in this <object value = "photo" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> photo </object> as well. I am so excited about the <object value = "counters" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "EMS"> counter space </object> I am gaining in my new layout! Please ignore the floor...it will be the last thing we do.

Speaking of counters, let me give you a sneak peek at what I decided to use on them. If you're a regular here, you know I wanted butcher block counters. Well, I did a ton of research on them and just could not commit to them. They are beautiful but do require a lot of upkeep and I just don't want to have to worry about them. We also didn't want to <object value = "car" id = "16" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "S"> drive </object> all the way to Tampa or Orlando to get them. The hubby had suggested tile, but I was adamant that I did NOT want tile. Nothing against it, it just wasn't the look I was going for. But then, the night after he suggested it, I had an epiphany! I thought, why not use wood look tile! Tile is so easy and durable, not to mention cheaper than anything else, and the wood look tile is beautiful.
So, check it out.....

Now this isn't installed, but I had to lay it out and see what it was going to look like. I am in LOVE!!! It is exactly the look I was going for. I couldn't be happier! I love the way the corner looks. I saw this idea online. What do you think?

Sadie thinks she is tired of the remodeling...lol!

I was really hoping we would be finished before I go back to work tomorrow, but it's OK. We have the hardest part done and after the <object value = "counters" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "MS"> counters </object> are finished, it will just be finish work....lights, sink, shelving, pantry, floor, etc. I'm so happy with it and can't wait to organize and decorate!

I hope you had a beautiful weekend and I hope your week is just as beautiful. I have a workshop in Tampa on Thursday, so several of the teachers and administrators from my school will be heading down there Wednesday after school. I am hoping we can run to Ikea so I can pick up a few goodies for the <object value = "kitchen" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ES"> new kitchen </object>, but it will depend on what the others want to do.
Until next time....