date: 5/28/2015
site: http://shullfamily.blogspot.com/2014/08/colorado-road-trip.html

TUESDAY, AUGUST 19, 2014

Colorado Road Trip
The Shull family just came back from a road trip.  I could have named this <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> post </object> The Longest Post Shay Has Ever Written, but I didn't.  Nevertheless, I apologize for the length...I wanted to fit the entire trip into this one <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> post </object>:).

We decided it was time to load the kids up and head out for beautiful Colorado.  We made a full circle...leaving Dallas and heading to Amarillo for the night, then cutting through New Mexico until we arrived in Breckenridge, Colorado.  When we came <object value = "home" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> home </object>, we went through Denver and then down through Kansas and Oklahoma until we were back to Dallas.  Both legs of the trip took about 15 hours.  

It was your typical road trip...there was scenery, lots of yummy food, a little puking, some site seeing, <object value = "car" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car sickness </object> and a <object value = "car" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> fender bender </object>.  You know, we did it Griswold style.  

As a side note (this will come into play at the end of the trip), back on May 5, the kids and I were in a <object value = "car" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car accident </object> that totaled my <object value = "car" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car </object>.  Since my <object value = "car" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car </object> was only a year old, I wanted to replace it with the exact same car...but there is a huge waiting list for this car now, so I was told by every dealership that would take 4 months to replace my <object value = "car" id = "2" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car </object>...and I chose to wait it out.  The first two months of the summer, I drove Andrew's wrapped car that has his face all over it (lucky me) and then the last two months, the dealership was able to provide me with a <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> loaner car </object>.  We drove the <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> loaner car </object> on this trip.  Keep this in mind ;).


Monday afternoon, we headed out to Amarillo to spend the night.  It's about a <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> 6 hour drive </object> from Dallas to Amarillo, TX.



My kids are so good in the <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car </object>.  I did a post here about traveling in the car with kids...but I really think it just takes a lot of practice.  Smith did this most of the way...watch <object value = "movies" id = "4" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> movies </object>.  (Several of you have asked me where we found the <object value = "iPad holders" id = "5" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> iPad holders </object> and they're from the Apple Store.)



And Kensington did this...play with her toys :).



We were so bored and desperate on the way to Amarillo that we stopped for Dairy Queen.  Andrew and I remembered that the last time we had a Blizzard was almost 9 years ago on the day we closed on our first <object value = "house" id = "6" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> house </object>.  Very random Shull fact :).



The next morning, I put on my car traveling uniform of <object value = "leggings" id = "7" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> leggings </object> and my <object value = "blardigan" id = "8" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> blardigan </object>...Sheaffer and Andrea were so jealous of the cold weather and comfy clothes :).



Breakfast at Cracker Barrel (a road trip requirement, no?).  Smith was roaring.



Back in the <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car </object> we go.  It was 8 hours from Amarillo to Breckenridge, Colorado.



About an hour from Amarillo, we found a baby cow in the middle of the road...luckily, my hubby grew up on a working farm with cattle, so he knew how to run it back through the fence to its mama.  #cowproblems



We made it to Breckenridge around 3:00 pm!  Woohoo!



My peeps enjoying beautiful Breckenridge!



I love my girl!  
(And listen, several of you have already asked about my <object value = "cross body bag" id = "9" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> cross body bag </object>...unfortunately, it is several years old.  I did a <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> post </object> on cross body bags here if you want to read it!)



After dinner at a brewery, the kids played and played by the water.  Not a bad view.



Everyone said we should eat at Crepes a la Cart (this outdoor crepe stand) but it started raining really hard, so Andrew stood in the rain to get our crepes and we ate them in the <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> car </object>.  Listen, these crepes were the best I've ever had...and I'm pretty much a crepe eating expert.  We ended up having them 3 nights in a row for dessert...sooooo good!


My kiddos said they were still hungry after dinner and crepes and they wanted a pizza.  Side note...the Shull gets don't eat much.  They can pretty much eat two bites and call it good until the next day.  They just never have been big eaters and they don't snack between meals...so, when they said they were hungry and wanted more to eat, we happily got them a little pizza to share.

Big mistake.

So....we were staying in the Beaver Run Resort (which was okay but not fabulous) and they upgraded us to a suite with a separate bedroom...the only catch is that there was only one king sized bed...so we decided that was fine and we would all four sleep together.  Fast forward to this evening and around 10:30, Kensington threw up everywhere.  In the bed.  Where we were all sleeping.  And by everywhere, I mean e.v.e.r.y.w.h.e.r.e.

Sigh.

We're pretty sure it was a mixture of too much pizza and altitude sickness.  As soon as it was over, she was good to go.  Smith slept through the entire ordeal.  We literally picked him up and moved him around to clean up and remove all the bedding and he never even opened an eyelid. 


The view from our room the next morning.



Breakfast at a local cafe.



After breakfast, we headed up to the top of Peak 8 for the fun!  My kids loved riding these gondolas!!







My kids had the BEST time at the top of Peak 8.  They love, love, loved everything about it!



On the ski lift about to do the Alpine Slide!



The boys



The girls :)


Andrew and I agreed that our favorite part of the trip was the scenic ski lift to the top where we were able to hike around.  This ski lift took about 30 minutes and we were all 4 able to ride together...it was so peaceful and beautiful.  



I looked down when we were hiking and laughed...I apparently hike like a city girl in my <object value = "shoes" id = "10" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> Toms </object>, <object value = "necklace" id = "11" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "ems"> Kendra Scott necklace </object> and Caramel Macchiato.



Smith loved our time at the very top.



Mom <object value = "selfie" id = "12" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> selfie </object> to end the day :).  We were waiting for Andrew to order our crepes...we all ordered the S'mores Crepe this time...goodness, it was so yummy!



The next morning, we were ready for a big day of horseback riding and fishing!



We took a 90 minute trail ride and oh goodness, it was so much fun!  We went up the mountain to the top of Peak 10 and back down.




After our morning of horseback riding, we stopped for BBQ and a great view :).



Andrew grew up fishing, so the kids wanted to fish too.  We brought the kids <object value = "fishing supplies" id = "13" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> rod and reels </object> from <object value = "home" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> home </object> so they could fish.  This is how Smith fished...cookie in hand, rod on leg.



It was so peaceful.



The only thing K caught was seaweed but boy, she was really, really proud of it :).



We ended the day with another crepe.  Listen people, they were that good.



On our last full day, the kids wanted to head back up to Peak 8 before we left.  Hubby and me on the gondola.






Back at the top of Peak 8 for more Alpine Sliding!  After a morning at the top, we drove the 45 minutes to Vail.



Everywhere we go, he always wants to hold my hand.



We had THE BEST German food in Vail.  You know me, I love German food.  German food is my very, very, very favorite kind of food!!  Woohoo!



It was such a fun day in Vail!



Kensington wanted to take our <object value = "picture" id = "14" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> picture </object>.  With all of those <object value = "selfie" id = "12" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "es"> selfies </object>, I forget that I'm only 5'3" compared to my 6'5" husband!



After Vail, we headed out...first stopping in Denver at Casa Bonita.  If you know what this is, I'm pretty sure you're laughing right now.  Andrew grew up eating here on every family trip to Colorado.  It's a Mexican restaurant like you've never seen...there is cliff diving.  Yes, cliff diving inside the Mexican restaurant.  My kids loved it!


Big fans of Casa Bonita!

We left Denver and <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> drove </object> to Salina, Kansas where we arrived at 2:00 am and stayed the night.  We got up at 7:30 and <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> drove </object> the rest of the way back to Dallas.

And in Oklahoma City, we were rear ended...in the <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> loaner car </object> we are driving because we were in a car accident.  That folks, is irony.

Thankfully, it was minor and we were able to <object value = "loaner car" id = "3" type = "perm" agreement = "m"> drive off </object> and head back to Texas (and thankfully, my new car arrives on Monday!).  In our 10 years of marriage, we have only had two car accident situations...both within a four month period.


Here we are just after crossing back into Texas.  We live about an hour from the Texas/Oklahoma border, so at this point, we thought we were in the clear.  

And then I got car sick.

Road trip fun.

I'm so thankful for this little 6 day journey with my family!  Nothing like over 30 hours of car time to really bring a family together.

The entire trip, we kept saying that it was all so perfect...except for one thing...there is a little girl on the other side of the world who wasn't with us.  The next Shull adventure...the four of us are packing up and heading there to bring her <object value = "home" id = "1" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> home </object>.  We are so ready to be a family of five.

On my <object value = "blog" id = "0" type = "perm" status = "final" agreement = "e"> foodie blog </object> today...



...a little party trick for serving puddings and trifles.

And don't forget, you have one more day to win one of these fabulous necklaces...



...click here for your chance to win!

XO